# Fernando Calvo

I am a full stack developer, focused on JavaScript and all its environment. I started working with PHP but moved quickly to JS and Node environments. Experience with cutting edge technology like Node, React, GraphQL, MongoDB... I've also had experience with devops tools like Docker, AWS, Azure...

Very interested on startups, as I tried to launch a startup, and I also have experience as dev architect and improving the ways of working in small team to follow methodologies like Agile/Scrum.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **FULL-STACK DEVELOPER, PIMBERLY - MANCHESTER**

03/2019 - current

Adding new features in a NodeJS/Marionette app. Starting the adoption of React and Serverless in the team.

## **UI DEVELOPER, BARCLAYS - MANCHESTER**

02/2019 - 03/2019

Working as front end engineer in the Corporate banking side.

### **FULL-STACK DEVELOPER, PARK-IT - BIRMINGHAM**

09/2017 - 01/2019

I joined to the team in the early stage. We built the microservices from scratch, and the front applications as well. We work with Node, RPC to communicate between services and GraphQL as the public API. The front apps are built with React, React Native and Relay. I took a key role in the team.

## FRONT-END DEVELOPER, MINDERA - LEICESTER

01/2017 - 09/2017

I started to work as a front end developer in an Angular 2 project in an international team. After that I am responsible of another project where I am working as a full stack developer, working with Angular in the frontend and Node in the backend. I am working with AWS: S3 and DynamoDB.

## FRONT-END DEVELOPER, PROPELLER - RUGBY

10/2016 - 12/2016

I worked as a frontend developer managing different sites based on WordPress. I developed the frontend for an internal project in React.

#### **FULL-STACK DEVELOPER, GAMELEARN - MADRID**

02/2015 - 09/2016

I started working as a backend developer in some projects with Symfony and MySQL. Here I learnt about agile, TDD and another good practices. Then I spent the most of the time developing some games based on Phaser, using libraries as Lodash, Backbone, Browserify, Grunt... and in the backend we used Node and Mongo. It was an incredible source of knowledge for me.

#### JUNIOR DEVELOPER, E-STRATEGIA - MADRID

06/2014 - 01/2015

I developed and maintained some websites with different CMS (WordPress, Drupal) and created a new website with Codeigniter.

## INTERN DEVELOPER, OPINNO - MADRID

03/2014 - 05/2014

I did my internships at Opinno working and learning about Drupal. We were developing some projects for MIT.

## **SKILLS & ABILITIES**

JavaScriptServerlessNodeJSMySQLReactMongoDBExpressAWS, AzureGraphQLCSS, LESS, SASSHTMLScrum

## **OTHER PROJECTS**

## **CO-FOUNDER AT MEZENAX**

03/2016 - 01/2018

I developed a crowdfunding platform for creators and artists in Spain with some friends. We developed the platform with Angular, PHP and MongoDB. We had some features implemented in Node. Everything was running in Azure. We had to manage the marketing campaigns and all the sides of a company.

## **EDUCATION**

CIVIL ENGINEER, UNIVERSIDAD POLITECNICA DE MADRID

2009 - 2013

WEB APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER, IES MIRASIERRA, MADRID

2012 - 2014